#### Contact

alok.proc@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ alokyadavonline (LinkedIn) pharmatalkonline.blogspot.com/ (Blog) alokyadav.brandyourself.com/ (Other)

### Top Skills

Sales Management Product Marketing Market Research

### Languages

Hindi English

#### Certifications

Building Deep Learning Applications with Keras 2.0

Al-ML Trainer Development Program

Statistics Foundations: 2

Deep Learning: Face Recognition

# Alok Yadav

Data Science and Machine Learning Expert

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

# Summary

Alok Yadav is Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning expert. Currently Working on Cognitive Automation providing solutions using Deep learning. Providing data science solutions Data science on cloud platform- AWS, Azure. He is also a freelance data science trainer

Specialties: Random Forest, SVM, KMeans, CNN, RNN, LSTM, NLP, Keras, Tensorflow, Spacy, AWS, Azure

# Experience

Tata Consultancy Services Machine Learning Specialist January 2018 - Present Mumbai Area, India

machine learning,natural language processing,deep learning,sentiment analysis,text mining,pattern recognition,nlp,topic modeling,text classification,entity recognition,python,mongodb,neural ,tableau,spark,nltk,data analysis,nosgl,Data Visualization, AWS, Sagemaker , Azure

UrbanPro.com
Data Science & Machine Learning Tutor
March 2019 - Present
Mumbai Area, India

Python , Data Science , Machine Learning , Natural Language Processing , Artificial Intelligence , R , Tableau

https://www.urbanpro.com/alokyadav

Imarticus Learning
Data Science Corporate Trainer
November 2019 - Present
Mumbai Area, India

- Data Science, Machine Learning program covered concepts and code in R and Python
- Data Science Prodegree program endorsed by GenPact

### Analytixpro

**Data Science Trainer** 

July 2019 - December 2019 (6 months)

Hyderabad Area, India

Data Science with Python-Globally Recognized IBM Certificate

**IBM Authorized Partner** 

- --Python Essentials for Data Science
- --Statistics for Data Science
- -- Data Science & Applied Machine Learning

#### IMS Proschool Pvt. Ltd.

Data Science Trainer, IMS Proschool Private Ltd,

May 2019 - December 2019 (8 months)

Mumbai Area, India

Data Science Course:

# Business Analytics- -National Skill Development Corporation ( NSDC) , NSE

Academy and IMS

Proschool

# Post Graduate Diploma in Data Science- Govt Approved

# Certificate in Data Science--NSDC & IMS Proschool

https://www.proschoolonline.com/data-science-course

#### Verzeo

Machine Learning & Artificial Intelligence Instructor , Mentor & Project Guide

July 2019 - August 2019 (2 months)

Mumbai Area, India

Machine Learning with Python -Internship Program

--Microsoft Technology Associate (MTA) Completion Certificate on Python.

Pace Career academy, Nidan Education & Skill Training Freelance Data Science Trainer

October 2018 - June 2019 (9 months)

Mumbai Area, India

Well versed in ML and deep learning concepts like SVM, Decision tree, Random forest, Bagging, Boosting, Naive Bayes, Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, KNN, K Means, ANN, CNN, RNN, LSTM etc.

University of Mumbai Project Guide June 2012 - May 2019 (7 years) Mumbai Area, India

Tata Consultancy Services
Senior Clinical Data Manager
June 2015 - December 2017 (2 years 7 months)
Mumbai Area, India

I worked as clinical data manager and was dealing with clinical trial data. My role involved Clinical

Data Management activities like discrepancy management, manual data review, lab

data management, query reconciliation using Oracle Clinical -SAS tool.

University Of Mumbai Visiting Faculty June 2012 - May 2015 (3 years) Mumbai Area, India

Marketing Management

# Education

Liverpool John Moores University

Master of Science -M.Sc, Machine Learning and Al · (2019 - 2020)

International Institute of Information Technology Bangalore PG Program-- Machine Learning & Al · (2019 - 2020)

SP Jain School of Global Management - Dubai, Mumbai, Singapore & Sydney

Professional Program in Big Data & Analytics, Machine learning ,Deep Learning, Data Science, Tableau, Hadoop , Spark , Natural Language Processing · (2016 - 2018)

University of Mumbai

Post Graduate Diploma in Applied Statistics, Multivariate Statistics- Market Reasearch-Forecasting · (2010 - 2011)

### University of Mumbai

MBA in Pharmaceutical Management, Pharmaceutical Sciences, Biostatistics in Clinical Research  $\cdot$  (2009 - 2010)